<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael Morris&#39; site</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael Morris&#39; site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assorted links, draft combine edition</title>
      <link>/2020/01/assorted-links-draft-combine-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/assorted-links-draft-combine-edition/</guid>
      <description>Today’s reading about the draft combine and the theme is that it doesn’t do very well predicting NFL performance.
As I read these studies, what really stands out is how difficult it is to measure individual player performance. A predictor can’t possibly do well if the performance measure is unreliable or not valid, and it’s clear there is a lot of be desired from the performance measures that are commonly available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft capital spent by position (2010-2019)</title>
      <link>/2020/01/draft-capital-by-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/draft-capital-by-position/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to examine:
 How much draft capital has been invested in different position groups over the last 10 years? Are there trends in investment?  Sources:
 Draft history Draft pick values  Here I looked at results for the 2010-2019 drafts, covering the last 10 years. To value draft capital, I focused on the Chase Stuart model, but I report the Jimmy Johnson model results below as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL analytics assorted links</title>
      <link>/2020/01/nfl-analytics-assorted-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/nfl-analytics-assorted-links/</guid>
      <description>What I’ve been reading:
 On predicting individual offensive line play
 Winning leads to rushing attempts, not the other way around
   early in games, it is more important to gain yards than just to run the ball for the heck of it, but at the end of the game the number of runs is more important than how many yards they gain.
  What the nerds mean when the say running backs don’t matter…and other great bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 NFL Draft Capital by Team</title>
      <link>/2020/01/2020-nfl-draft-capital-by-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/2020-nfl-draft-capital-by-team/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seahawks should pass more</title>
      <link>/2020/01/seahawks-should-pass-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/seahawks-should-pass-more/</guid>
      <description>The view from my seats
 The Seahawks are known as a run first team. The numbers strongly suggest that passing more would lead to a more successful offense.
It’s well known in the analytics community that passing is generally better than rushing. See here for some examples:
 https://thepowerrank.com/2018/09/24/the-surprising-truth-about-passing-and-rushing-in-the-nfl/ https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/for-a-passing-league-the-nfl-still-doesnt-pass-enough/ https://www.cmusportsanalytics.com/nfl-expected-points-nflscrapr-part-1-introduction-expected-points/  Here I’ll review some basic analyses to make that point in general and for the Seahawks in particular for the 2019 regular season.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>