<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael Morris&#39; site</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael Morris&#39; site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>nflfastR and how lucky is Seattle to have Russell Wilson?</title>
      <link>/2020/09/nflfastr-and-how-lucky-is-seattle-to-have-russell-wilson.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/nflfastr-and-how-lucky-is-seattle-to-have-russell-wilson.en-us/</guid>
      <description>The relatively new nflfastR package is pretty incredible. One command and you get a local SQLite database with 20 years of cleaned play by play data:
 update_db( dbdir = “/home/michael/Documents/NFL/”, dbname = “nflpbpdb”, tblname = “pbp_raw”, force_rebuild = FALSE)
 And you can run the same command to update with any new games. Incredible.
Playing around with it, one measure you get is completion percentage above expectation (CPOE), which takes into account the relative difficulty of each throw and the outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTHORR package now available</title>
      <link>/2020/09/rthorr-package.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/rthorr-package.en-us/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently made available my first public R package. RTHORR is designed to make it easy to run the randomaization test of hypothesized order relations (RTHOR; Hubert &amp;amp; Arabie, 1987). Terence Tracey, who wrote most of the original code, graciously agreed to let me make some minor alterations and turn his code into this package. Please see the link above for installation instructions and more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expect points added cheatsheet</title>
      <link>/2020/08/expect-points-added-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/expect-points-added-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Like everyone else I am hoping that we have NFL football this fall, but also like everyone else I want that to be safe (at least as far as football can be) from virus related problems. I doubt that will happen but we’ll see.
When sitting in the stands, I’ve sometimes mentioned the concepts of expected points (EP) and expected points added (EPA) but I’ve never had a great feel for how many EP a given situation was worth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring expected points added (EPA) by different play outcomes</title>
      <link>/2020/06/exploring-expected-points-added-epa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/exploring-expected-points-added-epa/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I looked at some run vs pass splits using expected points added (EPA). Here I’m going to explore 20 years of data to look at some basic but I think interesting things related to EPA using the great newish package nflfastr.
Let’s start with a review of EPA. By using models, analysts can estimate the expected number of points (EP) that accompany a given field position, down, distance, and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busses and bikes and parking</title>
      <link>/2020/05/busses-and-bikes-and-parking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/busses-and-bikes-and-parking/</guid>
      <description>A collection of thoughts on transportation in cities:
 Busses are underrated. They should be the backbone of urban public transportation. They are cost effective and can change according to demand (frequency and routes). Bus only lanes, preferences at stop lights, better signage with expected wait times and maps, and other measures can make them more effective. The virus makes this more challenging, admittedly, although I’m optimistic that we’ll eventually have some combination of vaccine, protective clothing, and behavioral practices that minimize risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus questions for later</title>
      <link>/2020/05/coronavirus-questions-for-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/coronavirus-questions-for-later/</guid>
      <description>Things I’m curious to read about in the coming years about coronavirus impacts:
 Work related
 Will companies become more friendly to remote work? Will they seek out remote employees as a form of resilience to future disease waves? Will they increase their demand for office space to give their employees more space or decrease their demand as they shift to remote work? Will a home office boost the value of one’s house more than before?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL draft capital and next year DVOA</title>
      <link>/2020/05/nfl-draft-capital-and-next-year-dvoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/nfl-draft-capital-and-next-year-dvoa/</guid>
      <description>I previously took a look at draft capital spent by team from 2010-2019 and draft capital by team by position over the same period. Here I will extend that analysis further with the question: Does draft capital spent have an impact on the subsequent year’s performance?
To do that, I’ll look at draft capital spent on offense and defense across the league and predict the following year’s DVOA. Draft capital will be determined using the Chase Stuart model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PFF&#39;s review on the NFL draft and positional value </title>
      <link>/2020/04/pff-s-review-on-the-nfl-draft-and-positional-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/pff-s-review-on-the-nfl-draft-and-positional-value/</guid>
      <description>Pro Football Focus has a new article looking at the positions that teams have spent the most draft capital on over the past few years. This is similar to what I did here three months ago.
Let me review what I like about their approach and add some comments:
 They used their own PFF WAR metric to measure draft capital of each pick. Although I don’t fully understand their approach, I like trying to quantify value in this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus assorted thoughts</title>
      <link>/2020/03/coronavirus-assorted-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/coronavirus-assorted-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Some random thoughts and observations:
 Widespread mask usage seem like a good idea If we have lots of easy cheap testing (and at home), it would be much easier to allow certain people to break quarantine and possibly donate blood to help others get well. Opening up the Seattle express lanes and certain other roads to bikes seem like a great limited duration idea. They are not needed at present traffic volumes, easy to monitor/police, and provide a needed entertainment outlet with so many other parks and outdoor options closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walt Disney World tips</title>
      <link>/2020/03/walt-disney-world-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/walt-disney-world-tips/</guid>
      <description>My family and I recently spent a day at Walt Disney World (Magic Kingdom) in Orlando. Here’s what I recommend if you are considering going yourself:
Before you book, strongly consider not going at all. My wife and I agreed after that even though our day went ok, it was a big effort in time and money and it probably wasn’t worth it. There are many other theme parks and places to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing Kirwan&#39;s predictions 10 years later</title>
      <link>/2020/02/reviewing-kirwan-s-predictions-10-years-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/reviewing-kirwan-s-predictions-10-years-later/</guid>
      <description>Pat Kirwan’s book with David Seigerman Take Your Eye Off the Ball was published in 2010. There is a second edition, published in 2015, but I’m focusing on a series of predictions made in the original in Chapter 14 (State of the Art Football).
Here I’ll review his predictions and make some of my own for the next 10 years. No huddle for all. Here Kirwan predicted that the pre play huddle would be phased out, with teams going into the huddle for 10 plays per half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL draft capital by position by team</title>
      <link>/2020/01/nfl-draft-capital-by-position-by-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/nfl-draft-capital-by-position-by-team/</guid>
      <description>Today’s question: What position groups have each team invested the most draft capital in over the past 10 NFL drafts (2010-2019)? I looked at overall leaguewide trends in draft capital from the last 10 years here.
This analysis might indicate that certain teams have a tendency to target certain position groups more than others. Let’s not overinterpret these results, though. Teams can bring in players through other means than the draft, such as resigning previous draftees, or signing free agents (veteran or undrafted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assorted links, draft combine edition</title>
      <link>/2020/01/assorted-links-draft-combine-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/assorted-links-draft-combine-edition/</guid>
      <description>Today’s reading about the draft combine and the theme is that it doesn’t do very well predicting NFL performance.
As I read these studies, what really stands out is how difficult it is to measure individual player performance. A predictor can’t possibly do well if the performance measure is unreliable or not valid, and it’s clear there is a lot of be desired from the performance measures that are commonly available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft capital spent by position (2010-2019)</title>
      <link>/2020/01/draft-capital-by-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/draft-capital-by-position/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to examine:
 How much draft capital has been invested in different position groups over the last 10 years? Are there trends in investment?  Sources:
 Draft history Draft pick values  Here I looked at results for the 2010-2019 drafts, covering the last 10 years. To value draft capital, I focused on the Chase Stuart model, but I report the Jimmy Johnson model results below as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL analytics assorted links</title>
      <link>/2020/01/nfl-analytics-assorted-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/nfl-analytics-assorted-links/</guid>
      <description>What I’ve been reading:
 On predicting individual offensive line play
 Winning leads to rushing attempts, not the other way around
   early in games, it is more important to gain yards than just to run the ball for the heck of it, but at the end of the game the number of runs is more important than how many yards they gain.
  What the nerds mean when the say running backs don’t matter…and other great bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 NFL Draft Capital by Team</title>
      <link>/2020/01/2020-nfl-draft-capital-by-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/2020-nfl-draft-capital-by-team/</guid>
      <description>With the Seahawks season over, I was curious to look at the current 2020 NFL draft capital of the Seahawks vs the rest of the NFL. The final draft order will not be set until after the Superbowl, but most of it is set as of today.
Here I looked at draft capital in two ways: Chase Stuart’s numbers the the older Jimmy Johnson numbers.
The Seahawks GM, John Schneider, has often traded down and generated additional picks (and surplus capital), so it would not be surprising to find him doing so again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seahawks should pass more</title>
      <link>/2020/01/seahawks-should-pass-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/seahawks-should-pass-more/</guid>
      <description>The view from my seats
 The Seahawks are known as a run first team. The numbers strongly suggest that passing more would lead to a more successful offense.
It’s well known in the analytics community that passing is generally better than rushing. See here for some examples:
 https://thepowerrank.com/2018/09/24/the-surprising-truth-about-passing-and-rushing-in-the-nfl/ https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/for-a-passing-league-the-nfl-still-doesnt-pass-enough/ https://www.cmusportsanalytics.com/nfl-expected-points-nflscrapr-part-1-introduction-expected-points/  Here I’ll review some basic analyses to make that point in general and for the Seahawks in particular for the 2019 regular season.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>